We're going around the wealthiest golf courses in
all of Texas asking millionaires how they became rich.
I bought a landscape supply company in New Braunfels
and I sold it after four years for $42 million.
How much did you sell it for?
We sold it for about $38 million.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
A lot.
Is it in the seven digits?
Yes.
Okay.
All right, guys, I think we're pulling up
on the first country club slash golf course.
We're going to Austin Country Club.
It's going to be a long shot.
We have no idea if
this place is gated or not.
We're going to try to maybe ask if we can get in
and get some interviews just off the pure luck of our channel.
So let's get to it.
Hey, brother, quick question for you.
I know it's a long shot.
We were going to try to
see if we could do some interviews.
I can't let you unless
you're a member or a resident.
It's going to be tough today trying
to go to these private golf courses.
They don't know who we are.
We're just trying to get in and get these interviews.
But at the end of the day,
we've got to mix up the game plan.
Yeah, well, I already found the second course.
It's kind of like a private.
Resort that we're going to head to.
So about 15 minutes away.
But hopefully we can get in there
and find out how these millionaires got rich.
We're approaching the second golf course.
And hopefully we're going to be able to get in
and maybe snack some interviews with some multimillionaires while we're here.
So the gate was open and
we were able to sneak in.
We just got to our next golf course.
Only problem is it is a private
course and there are attendants in every hole.
So hopefully we can find a way
to scheme and get some of these interviews.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
A little over a million.
What was the importance of following
your passion for you throughout your career?
It made me a very successful hospital administrator doing something I love
and it made a big difference in a lot of people's lives.
What led to your success to be able
to work your way up to run hospitals?
Being street smart.
Always taking a perspective that you can learn something
every day and not be too full of yourself.
How can someone really start their path
to becoming financially free in today's world?
Live within your means.
My philosophy early on, I had a mentor who said, live on
what you made five years ago and invest and bank the rest.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Probably close to 1.5.
1.5 million.
Were you ever a business owner?
I am right now.
Yeah. What kind of business are you running right now?
We own a company that
has a golf putting training aid.
What advice would you tell someone
who's starting a business this year?
Make sure you have a number of
people who have been successful at launching
startups. Give you advice. Make sure
you got a strong business plan.
You got a strong marketing, social media presence and
make sure you got your funding in place. One of
my people that I really look up to is
Sir Richard Branson. He says that customers or your clients
aren't the most important priority. Your people are.
If you take care of your people, they'll take
care of your customers. So I really believe in that.
We're taking a bit of an intermission in this
video real quick. We got our boy James here from
the school of hard knocks and our new friend Will.
We are actually going to do a challenge real quick.
First of three, Will's nice enough to let us
play with him. So yeah, let's get to it boys.
Oh my God.
Ooh.
Hey, he's a...
He's a power up.
Oh.
Almost, almost.
Geez. We may have to play the two, bro.
Will could be the first one on the board.
Woo.
We're going to check in with James and Will
later, but for now, let's go get some more interviews.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
So I was a golf professional for a while and
then I got out of the business and now I'm in
IT sales.
What has been your secret to sales throughout your career?
Just put myself in the customer's shoes.
I really try to build relationships on
just being so personal and real with folks and
just try to listen to what their challenges are.
When someone is a no though, what's
your strategy to convert them to a yes?
I like to find out why. Is it competition?
Is it pricing? Where is it? It sets me up
better for the next time.
What would be your best
financial advice to the younger generation?
Stay out of debt and don't
get divorced. It's cheaper to keep her.
I love that.
And that's true because I've been divorced and it
cost me quite a bit. So I like that advice.
Right. What are you doing exactly?
I'm a project architect at a
high-end design firm here in Austin.
What would be your best advice for the younger generation?
What would be your best financial advice to
the younger generation that you wish someone told you
when you were coming out of college?
I went to school with a bunch
of people that didn't go to college
that are as financially free as I am.
And that's because they made good investments. They became
business owners and then quickly they understood that
they needed to invest. So if you can invest
your money early on, the earlier, the
better. So professional golfer turned tech salesman,
another tech salesman, and then an architect.
Pretty cool interviews and some pretty insightful
game from them. So we're going to keep
running these interviews up and hope you guys are
enjoying the content.
Make sure that you subscribe to our channel and
hit the bell so you don't miss any of our
new videos. And we'll see you in the next video.
You leave a like and you subscribe because we've
got tons of amazing content on the way and stay
tuned for the end for some real
game. We've been getting some really good
interviews today, but let's go tap in on Will
and James and see how that golf game's going.
Whoa, that's going to be a tough second one.
Oh, no way. No way. No way.
Come on, dad. I'm not the
boy. Whoa, boys. Come on, dad.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
A lot.
Is it in the seven digits?
Yes.
Okay.
What is the best piece of advice
that you would tell your younger self?
Well, I would say, first of all,
college degree is important, but it's not imperative.
I think in this country, you can start
a business. You can go to the SBA,
you can borrow two or $300,000. And if you have
a thing that you like to do, you can start it.
I did not finish University of Texas. I started
a company 50 years ago with $67 a bank. We're
the largest company in town that what we do.
What is the biggest mindset you
have? What is your biggest mindset?
Mindset change that is needed
in order to become a multimillionaire?
Humbleness. If you do everything right, it
all takes care of itself. And if you
live right and you believe there's a guy upstairs
that takes care of you and you live down that
channel, then a lot of good things come to
you that you didn't even know were coming to you.
What's your best financial advice to the younger
generation that maybe you wish someone told you
coming out of school?
You have to find out what you're made of. I mean,
are you an outgoing guy? Are you going to open a
restaurant? Are you going to go to work for Dell?
You have to decide who you are. You work for Dell,
you make a couple hundred thousand dollars a year, and
you're going to go to work for Dell. You're going
to make a couple hundred thousand dollars a
year, and you're going to enjoy your life.
If you want to go into business, then
you have to decide what are you interested in,
and then you decide how do you build that. Then
you go find out from other people that have done
it. So there's no right answer. What
industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
Software, where I was a CEO of a software company.
What was the name of it?
PostUp. It was sold to Upland Software
here in Austin, Texas, a public company.
How much did you sell it for?
We sold it for about $38 million.
What was the biggest thing that you
implemented throughout your company to ultimately scale it
to the point that it got to
where you were able to sell it?
We were able to sell it for millions of dollars.
Built a great team. It's all about the
people, all about putting good people in places that
they're going to be successful at, and developing
people, and getting everybody on the same page so
that they're working together and communicating
effectively. That's what it's all about.
How did you break into the tech industry?
Well, I worked at Sony first. I
got my first job seven years at Sony,
then I went to Dell Computers for
seven years, and then I got into Suffer.
What was the biggest challenge that
you faced running a major company,
and how were you able to overcome that?
Challenges are getting people to focus on working
together and not against each other. So I worked
at big companies. We had a lot of power.
Yeah.
There was politics going on. It was hard to manage
it. When you get to a small team and you
own that small team, you can remove the politics
of focus on things like the customer and putting
out a good solution and a good product and
things that are important. That's why I love working at
smaller companies than large ones.
Hey, I mean, sometimes you don't want all
the bells and whistles. You don't want all the
flashy stuff. Sometimes you really got to get down
to the nitty gritty, the challenges. What are the
hard things about running a company that we got
to ask these people? Because ultimately, in order to
get to that success, you got to get through
all the bad stuff too. That was a great interview,
but it's 1-1 right now in the golf game with
James and Will. Let's go see who gets the next point.
Look at that. That's a stroke right
there. That was good. That was solid.
Oh, man.
Oh, my God. Get out of here.
Give me that. Give me that. Let's go.
Will just took the point to go up 2-1 on
James. But for now, let's go check back in with
the interviews and get some more game.
What is the best piece of advice
that you would tell your younger self?
Fail. Fail a lot. Second, I would always say
teach this to a lot of young athletes. As fast
as you can, find a mentor that's specific to what
you want to be, what you want to do. That'll let
you know what allows you to excel. What was the
most amount of money that you ever made in a
single year? Reportable to the IRS was a little
over a million. And with that, it's more money,
more problems. If you don't learn how to manage
the money, keep the money, and grow the money,
you know, shame on you again. How can
someone start their path to becoming wealthy in 2023?
Remember, there's a tremendous amount of wealth that's
out there that's above my age. So the
challenge that I see with a lot of people that
are younger than me and younger than you or at
your age, they don't always have those personal
skills. The faster they can develop those personal
skills, the better they're going to be. And I
think that's a great point. And I think that's
where they're going to be. What's the best
industry that people should be looking to get
into? Or where should people really look to
put their money? Industry-wise, as we get older,
medical is never one of those things that's going
to go away. Medical has always been one of those
things that allowed me to expand and to grow.
What is the best piece of advice that you would
tell your younger self? Start your own business.
Did you end up becoming a business owner?
I graduated UT, then I went to Wharton, worked
for KPMG, PWC, and then got hired by a company
called Union Carbide. Then I became the president
of Union Carbide. I got disenchanted over time
with corporate
America and decided to start my own business.
And I bought a landscape supply company in
New Braunfels. And I sold it
after four years for $42 million.
What is the first step that someone should really take
to make it more than just an idea of wanting
to start a business? The number one thing is
that there's so much capital out there. With a good
idea, you can get capital. And you don't
need to have investors. Investors really are problematic.
But you can go to the SBA and you
can take out a $3 million loan with $150,000 down.
You know, it's basically guaranteed by the
government and that'll catapult you into kind
of your starting spot. If you want to buy
a business for a million, then you need 50 grand.
How can someone really scale their business? Or
what was the biggest thing that you did that
scaled your business? Believing in growth, number
one. Constantly looking forward, not being scared.
Buying more trucks when people were not convinced trucks
were a good idea. And every time we bought
one, it made more money. Hiring more people
when I could tell people were stressed out outside.
Buying good gear. Outsourcing all the service size so we
could focus on business. It is 2-1 in the golf game.
It is 2-1 in the golf game between James and Will. Is
Will going to be able to close it out? Let's go see.
Oh man. Dang. All right. Good shot right there.
Come on.
Here we go. Oh, game.
Good game. Wow. Good game, man.
Make sure that you leave a like on the video
and you subscribe to the channel because we have tons
of great content coming on the way. And click
the link right here to watch us go boon-nocking
around one of the wealthiest neighborhoods in
Texas asking millionaires how they got rich.